416 841 7647 lana.milanovich@gmail.com 202-1529 Queen Anne Ave N. in Seattle, WA

LANA MILANOVICH

As a **project leader**, I work for the emergence of flatter, nimbler, more transparent, and more capable organizations. My focus is on ensuring efficiency: team efficiency by **removing impediments**, external and internal, and empowering teammates to stay focused so that they can contribute to their full potential; and company efficiency by **creating transparency** and facilitating uninterrupted flow of information. My education and experience, which includes the study of mathematical systems (computer science), business systems (management & entrepreneurship), visual systems (photography & design), and human systems (psychology), covers many key aspects of software production, enabling me to be successful in demanding technical oversight roles by **serving my teams** well.

COMPETENCIES

Software Engineering Solid technical expertise with over 7 years of hands-on software development experience building

enterprise Java applications on a stack of open-source technologies

Team Leadership Managed teams of up to 14 people responsible for a \$1.5M budget

People Development Built cohesive teams through coaching, 1-on-1s, constructive feedback, team building, and conflict

resolution. Professionally trained in coaching and group dynamics

Project Management Able to select and blend processes and practices as appropriate for a specific environment and drive

projects throughout the entire development lifecycle, working with vendors, clients, and distributed

teams

Product Management Applied the Lean Startup approach to formulate hypotheses and iteratively arrive at a solid MVP

through validated learning

Communications Experienced presenter, facilitator, and trainer, working with software teams, stakeholders,

executives, vendors, and clients. Able to convey complex technical concepts to both technical and

non-technical audiences

Consulting 6+ years in the professional services business, with a strong focus on the customer

CERTIFICATIONS

Project Management Professional PMP / Professional Scrum Master PSM / Sun Certified Java Programmer SCJP

TECHNICAL SKILLS Languages & Frameworks

Java, Spring (IoC, WebMVC, Security), Web Services (REST, SOAP), DB (Oracle, MySQL, MSSQL), ORM (Hibernate), HTML, CSS, SASS, Javascript, jQuery, Angular, Bootstrap, Testing (JUnit, Mockito), Test Automation (Selenium), Mobile (Android, Xamarin), OS (Windows, Unix-like), Database Modeling, Design Patterns

Prototyping & Communication of Design

Photoshop, Fireworks, Sketch, Balsamiq, Axure, Visio

Collaboration

VCS (Git, SVN), Build (Ant, Maven, Gradle, Grunt, Gulp), CI (Bamboo, Jenkins, Sonar), Infrastructure (Docker, AWS, Azure), Project Management (Jira, Target Process, Trello, Gannter), Code Review (FishEye + Crucible, Reviewboard)

EDUCATION & PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Computer Science, Masters Degree	Belarusian State University	2003 - 2008
Technology Management, Degree	Belarusian State University	2007 - 2008
Photography and Production, Diploma	Minsk School of Photography	2009 - 2011
Psychotherapy, Prof. Certificate	Gestalt Institute of Toronto	2011 - 2015
Entrepreneurship	MaRS Startup Incubator	2014 - 2014

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, Technical Project Manager

Architech / Toronto

2015 - 2016

Completed five R&D projects assessing the applicability of emerging technologies (computer vision, no-touch gesture interaction) to building digital experiences for brick-and-mortar stores. Two projects resulted in further development and deployment at the flagship locations of a major Canadian retailer in Toronto and Vancouver.

Led a team of four during an intensive twelve-week engagement with a startup in developing the founder's idea from high-level vision through technical proof of concept to a functional product prototype, which led to securing additional funding.

Managed a portfolio of projects, communicating schedules, risks, technical challenges, hypotheses, solutions, and cost impact to clients' technical and executive personnel.

Advocated for, sought budget and worked with the design strategy team to execute in-house and external user testing sessions to validate UX and value assumptions, which resulted in over \$100K budget savings and improved product.

Provided technical expertise to account managers and business analysts to assess project feasibility, scoping, and requirements gathering. Estimated effort and created budgets, schedules, and resource plans for confirmed engagements.

Contributed to client-facing presentations and technical solution pitches that translated into profitable partnerships for the company. Took the initiative to rapidly learn technology outside the stack of ongoing projects to provide expertise during discovery sessions with new clients.

Promoted DevOps culture adoption in the company by introducing CI/CD practices on my projects and promoting successful solutions to other teams. Created a multi-step deployment pipeline using a series of Jenkins plugins and set up information radiators, which improved visibility into build status and response times.

Took the initiative to set up advanced Jira workflows and reporting on another team's enterprise project with elevated security and reporting requirements, which provided a previously unavailable level of visibility into project status and helped advise the client on the necessary process changes by pinpointing bottlenecks to reduce cycle time.

Delivered company-wide technical training and talks with up to 40 attendees. As an external facilitator, led retrospective and brainstorming sessions for other teams. Provided Agile training and mentoring to new hires.

Software Engineer, Consultant

Destiny Solutions / Toronto

2012 - 2014

Designed new features, debugged problems, and developed solutions on all fronts with Struts-based UI and J2EE / SQL Server on the server-side. Worked directly with clients to understand requirements and work out viable solutions.

Enhanced the billing system to allow new transaction types and payment gateway integrations. Ensured correctness and prevented regression issues by implementing an extensive test harness.

Modernized the front-end on a legacy system to enable responsive layouts and mobile views.

Ensured, through rigorous peer review, adherence to security and accessibility guidelines and regulations such as CASL and WCAG 2.0 / AODA, as well as security standards.

Co-Founder Digiverse Apps / Toronto 2012 - 2014

Drove the development of six Xamarin mobile applications from RFP to requirements gathering through design and implementation to app store publishing.

Analyzed RFPs and applied technical expertise to craft comprehensive responses that won business in the competitive mobile development market.

Managed the engineering team and coordinated offshore designers, content producers, and marketing specialists.

Software Engineer, Team Leader

Exigen Insurance / Toronto

2007 - 2012

Contributed to core system development as a software engineer. Worked on document degeneration, rating and policy administration engines with JSF front-end and J2EE (Spring / Hibernate) back-end.

Clarified business requirements, performed gap analysis, and collaborated with platform, product management, and core development teams in the design of robust solutions that were successfully pitched to clients.

Coordinated local and offshore resources, translated business requirements into technical specifications, created WBS for the team.

Completed over 10 proof of concepts and product customizations and provided technical expertise during sales sessions in Europe and North America.

Software Engineer, Intern

EPAM Systems, Intetics / Minsk

before 2007

Contributed to engineering efforts on enterprise Java projects using open source technologies.